Guide to the Papers of the New Almaden Corporation, 1928-1944
Department of Special Collections
Schuette, Curt Nicholas. Papers of the New Almaden Corporation,
1928-1944
M0716
Schuette, Curt Nicholas
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Schuette was the general manager of the mining operation at New Almaden Mines from 1940 to 1945, when it was owned by the New Almaden Corporation. General and personal correspondence to and from the general manager,1943-1944, and business statements related to New Almaden Corporation. Included are two reports by C.N. Schuette, one on the condition of the Harry Shaft, 1939, and the other a comprehensive evaluation of the mining potential of the New Almaden property, 1935. Also included is a 5-page letter from the donor, Michael Cox, giving background information about the Schuettes and their connection to the mine as well as some photocopied photos of them.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Michael F. Cox, in memory of Curt and Erna Schuette, 1994.
Biography
Schuette was the general manager of the mining operation at New Almaden Mines from 1940 to 1945, when it was owned by the New Almaden Corporation.
Scope and Content
General and personal correspondence to and from the general manager,1943-1944, and business statements related to New Almaden Corporation. Included are two reports by C.N. Schuette, one on the condition of the Harry Shaft, 1939, and the other a comprehensive evaluation of the mining potential of the New Almaden property, 1935. Also included is a 5-page letter from the donor, Michael Cox, giving background information about the Schuettes and their connection to the mine, as well as some photocopied photos of them.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Cox, Michael F.; Frederick, Francis.; Newbold, F.E.; Schuette, Erna.; Sexton, William Lord.; New Almaden Corporation.; Mercury.; Mines and mineral resources--California.; Mining engineering.
Collection Contents
- Collection information: Copies of photos of Curt and Erna Schuette. Floppy disked containing scanned (.BMP) photos. "The Operation of New Almaden Corporation, 1940-1946" by C. N. Schuette (copy). (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous travel items from envelope marked "Trip..."(1935). (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous New Almaden Correspondence(1928 - 1945). (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence between C. N. Schuette and F. E. Newbold(1943 - 1944). (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "Report on the New Almaden Quicksilver Mine, Santa Clara County, California" by C. N. Schuette (1935)-first draft. With correspondence from CNS to William Lord Sexton. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "Report on the New Almaden Quicksilver Mine, Santa Clara County, California" by C. N. Schuette -bound copy.(1935) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Report on the New Almaden Quicksilver Mine, Santa Clara County, California" by C. N. Schuette -amended copy, with correspondence from Drinker, Biddle & Reath(1935-1940). (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Report on the present Condition of the Harry Shaft of the New Almaden Mine"(1939). (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Maps and drawings. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- New Almaden Corporation financial statements. (Box 1, Folder 10)